<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://curiosity54.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://curiosity54.github.io//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-11-13T22:12:28+00:00</updated><id>https://curiosity54.github.io//feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Personal and research page of Jigyasa Nigam. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">My world is burning</title><link href="https://curiosity54.github.io//blog/2024/my-world-is-burning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My world is burning"/><published>2024-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://curiosity54.github.io//blog/2024/my-world-is-burning</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://curiosity54.github.io//blog/2024/my-world-is-burning/"><![CDATA[<p>Another poem that feels so apt</p> <p><em>My world is burning</em></p> <blockquote> <p>Found myself here in the dark, in the midst of ruins, ashes, smoke and flames <br/> My world is burning in ways more than one, nothing could ever be the same<br/> Feeling less and less like myself, each passing minute, every other hour<br/> Don’t know how to tame the fire, to ask for help - I have lost all words, all power<br/> Bright blue water, cool breeze and the scent of tropical flowers: was it too good to be true?<br/> Is it me, have I just “burnt” out? Or is the reality undeniably all that ensues<br/> <br/> My world is burning, fish and turtles choke, due to people’s actions unplanned<br/> Leaves’ve crumpled, bird song’s muted, air’s polluted and lake’s turned to sand,<br/> It’s time to change, eh, mate? Not all our interactions need be a transaction<br/> I dream of a world where we change our ways and take some action<br/> <br/> My world is burning, a mother clenches on for life for her dying son<br/> Shackled spirits, prisoners of war, bloodshed, bombs and guns<br/> Why can’t we muster some courage to stop, for peace and quiet?<br/> I dream of a world without terrorism, subjugation and race riots<br/> <br/> My world is burning, abuses hurled, beaten black and blue, I got blamed<br/> For provoking an ‘innocent man’ to be lustful and violent - that’s how I got raped?!<br/> Where my identity, orientation, I decide - where I won’t be labeled or commodified<br/> I dream of a world where I’d be me, not only someone’s daughter, wife or merchandise<br/> <br/> Should I fight for my conviction or lament these fantasies that we would never realize?<br/> Oh how I hope the dream of reclaiming my power, strength, and sanity would materialize<br/> The raging fire somehow lights an internal candle of hope<br/> I dream of rising like a phoenix from the ashes, that’s the only way I can cope<br/> Nightmares will fade, paving the way to a beautiful, imminent transformation<br/> Rejoice and cheer as together we behold and enable the dawn of a new creation! 🤩<br/></p> </blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another poem that feels so apt]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Uprooting, challenging, …</title><link href="https://curiosity54.github.io//blog/2024/uprooting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Uprooting, challenging, …"/><published>2024-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://curiosity54.github.io//blog/2024/uprooting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://curiosity54.github.io//blog/2024/uprooting/"><![CDATA[<p>Scrolling through my archives today, found this poem I wrote almost 7 years ago, that still inspires me today!</p> <blockquote> <p>Longing eyes, shackled spirit, bowed head- veiled <br/> Subjecting to this oppression- I failed!<br/> Standards, restrictions and stereotypes unfurl<br/> Pride and ambitions subdued just because I am a girl!<br/> Refuse to be subordinated or comply, I rebel<br/> In my own quixotic world of justice and equality, I dwell!<br/> I am proud of being a woman<br/> For I am not prey to such ideologies inhumane<br/> It makes me dance with joy..that I am different from the crowd<br/> Soaring like a free bird through the stars and the happy clouds<br/> I will not be invisible or silent for any long<br/> This is my long suppressed voice, my song<br/> Education, insight and courage have empowered<br/> Certainly, I will not back down and be a coward<br/> Will not bow to restrictions and patriarchy<br/> Demolish this unjustifiable hierarchy<br/> Tired of being subjected to your whims and fancies<br/> Why associate femininity with only roses and pansies?<br/> You can only lock away books, opportunities and rights<br/> But cannot restrict my might or limit the power of my mind<br/> Resilient, strong, empowered and tough<br/> The journey has been rough, but now it’s enough.<br/> Now, I spread my wings and far I fly<br/> Not one of your plotted schemes can stop me, whatever you try.<br/> The non-conformist spirit has been ignited<br/> Spirit, soul and aspirations united<br/> No more domination, blinding or imposing your desire<br/> Freedom and happiness bring a world much higher.<br/> Break o break all shackles and chains<br/> Free myself from all the fears and pains<br/> Burn up trepidation, violence and cruelty in flames<br/> A world where I will not get the blame<br/> For provoking an ‘innocent man’ to rape<br/> As to why domestic violence did take shape<br/> A world where I can decide<br/> My sexual orientation would not subdue my pride!<br/> Where I will not be labelled or commodified<br/> Not known only as someone’s daughter, wife or merchandise.<br/> Alas this world is only an illusion<br/> Unless we act and shatter the delusion<br/> Think, reflect and rewrite our destiny<br/> Based on the tenets of equality and harmony<br/> Sow the seeds of courage and freedom in our heart<br/> Create a world that stands apart!<br/></p> </blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scrolling through my archives today, found this poem I wrote almost 7 years ago, that still inspires me today!]]></summary></entry></feed>